<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-06-22T14:09:28+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">James Posse Hunt</title><subtitle>Blog about my attempt to get back into tech. Also a portfolio.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Portfolio</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/update/2025/06/22/portfolio/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Portfolio" /><published>2025-06-22T12:35:00+09:00</published><updated>2025-06-22T12:35:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/update/2025/06/22/portfolio</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/update/2025/06/22/portfolio/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="portfolio-updates">Portfolio Updates</h1>

<p>This week, I made progress on the site, adding the resume page.</p>

<p>I also started working on the first app for my portfolio, which I call DD.</p>

<h2 id="dd">DD</h2>
<p>DD is a tool I started work on 3 years ago. I was starting to get into dungeons and dragons with my friends, and starting to run games in a class I taught at the time, STEAM Masters, after the children had finished their work. I, however, don’t have dice.
My solution was to write a very simple program in Python using randint, and over time added Tkinter to give it a GUI.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/DDPic.png" alt="DD UI Screenshot" /></p>

<p>This gives me output like this:</p>

<p><img src="/assets/DDPic2.png" /></p>

<p>As well as this, it has half-baked character sheet functionality that I don’t believe I ever published as it was clearly unfinished.</p>

<h3 id="so-whats-the-plan">So What’s the Plan?</h3>

<p>A complete overhaul, starting from scratch with a new UI built in DearPyGui (credit to Github user hoffstadt, repo found <a href="https://github.com/hoffstadt/DearPyGui">here</a>), a new file structure, character management, modularity and more features in mind.</p>

<p>I started the rebuild with the logic for dice rolling (the simple part) and will be working toward a first release soon - so stay tuned and once again thanks for reading!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Portfolio Updates]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/update/2025/06/15/welcome/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome!" /><published>2025-06-15T13:12:00+09:00</published><updated>2025-06-15T13:12:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/update/2025/06/15/welcome</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/update/2025/06/15/welcome/"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome, and I hope you’re well.
This is my first time blogging seriously, and I hope to keep at it to keep myself accountable and give a glimpse into what I’m doing.</p>
<h2 id="who-am-i">Who am I?</h2>
<p>My name is James Posse Hunt. I’m an Irishman from Tallaght, living in Aichi, Japan. I work at an eikaiwa called NOVA until next week, have a BSc in Computing with Software Development and I’m looking to get back into tech, so the blog is intended as a way to keep a record of my work. My plan is weekly updates each Sunday.</p>

<h2 id="the-plan">The Plan</h2>
<p>I plan to keep my eyes open while making demonstrable progress on dusting off skills I haven’t used in a while. The first plan, to look into, is an AWS Certification, and I’ll study for that along with studying Japanese. I plan to have that, and be at least JLPT N5, by the end of this year. The long term goal is to get up to at least N3 over the next couple years to be able to function well here.</p>

<p>I work for an eikaiwa called NOVA that was a good way to get me into Japan, but isn’t much of a career. They offer relatively low pay with very high expectations (I’ve gotten moaned at for yawning in class) and it got to a point where I was so frustrated, I just couldn’t do it anymore, so I handed in my months’ notice which ends next week (my last working day is the 23rd of this month).</p>

<p>Stay tuned for updates, and thanks for reading!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome, and I hope you’re well. This is my first time blogging seriously, and I hope to keep at it to keep myself accountable and give a glimpse into what I’m doing. Who am I? My name is James Posse Hunt. I’m an Irishman from Tallaght, living in Aichi, Japan. I work at an eikaiwa called NOVA until next week, have a BSc in Computing with Software Development and I’m looking to get back into tech, so the blog is intended as a way to keep a record of my work. My plan is weekly updates each Sunday.]]></summary></entry></feed>